A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of the Vice President, Media Projects, Office Files of Andrea L. Taylor FA684
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Office of the Vice President, Media Projects, Office Files of Andrea L. Taylor
1971-1999
Rockefeller Archive Center
Taylor, Andrea
Ford Foundation
FA684
23.32 Cubic Feet 60 document containers and one half document container
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in seven series:
1. Community Foundations, 1988-1989
2. Subject Files on the Soviet Union, Eastern Europe, and Brazil, 1986-1990
3. Innovations in State and Local Government, 1986-1992
4. Changing Relations Project, America Becoming Documentary, 1983-1991
5. Media Projects, 1971-1999
6. Council on Foundations, 1990-1993
7. Correspondence Files, 1993-1996
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Rockefeller Archive Center received ten accessions containing Andrea Taylor's files from the Ford Foundation between 2012 and 2021: Accessions 2018:018, 2012:084, 2019:018, 2019:027, 2019:048, 2019:077, 2019:093, 2019:067, 2019:109, and 2021:086.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains correspondence with grantees, press releases, background materials on media grantmaking institutions, memos, drafts of Ford publications, trip files, subject files, meeting invitations, articles, grant proposals, invitations to film screenings and festivals, conference files, and other materials created and received by Andrea Taylor in her roles as media officer and founder and director of Media Projects at the Ford Foundation.
The files within the collection pertain to documentaries, public radio, public broadcasting, media grantmakers and media organizations, media and public policy, social justice and civil rights, the Innovations in State and Local Government awards program, the work of community foundations, museums, and media portrayal of HIV/AIDS.
AIDS (Disease) in mass media; African American mass media; Community foundations; Diversity; Documentary films; Independent filmmakers; Mass media; Public broadcasting; Public radio; Public service television programs
- Community Foundations, 1988-1989; 1; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains conference materials, grant information, and news releases related to the 1989 Leadership Program for Community Foundations organized by the Ford Foundation and MacArthur Foundations. The series also contains background information on various community foundations.
  - Leadership Program for Community Foundations - Conference/Announcement, 1989 January (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Awardees (Community Foundations), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fall Conference for Community Foundations, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - El Paso Community Foundation, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Faxed Material (Community Foundations), 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Leadership Program for Community Foundations, Ford Foundation/MacArthur Foundation, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - News Release Drafts/Finals (Community Foundations), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - RGA (Community Foundations), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Subject Files on Soviet Union, Eastern Europe, and Brazil, 1986-1990; 2; 1.14 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes
  The series contains subject files on the Soviet Union, Eastern Europe, and Brazil used to plan, prepare for, and carry out work-related trips. In 1989, Taylor was a member of the Council on Foundations' delegation of twenty-five foundation executives and trustees who were invited to visit the Soviet Union. She traveled to Brazil in 1989 to review Ford Foundation media projects.
  - Reading Materials - Soviet Union, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Soviet Culture and Communication Under Gorbachev Conference Pamphlet, Atlanta, Georgia, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Interim Report of Soviet and East European Study Group, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Soviet East European Group, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Report of the Soviet and East European Study Group Discussion at September 1989 Board Meeting, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Soviet and Eastern Europe - News Release/Letters of Inquiry, 1990 February 14 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Coucil on Foundations Soviet Trip, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Sharon Tennison, Center for U.S.-U.S.S.R. Initiatives, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - U.S. Philanthropy and the Soviet Union - Conference May 22-24, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 3220 Gallery USSR Newsletters, 1989 April-November (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Soviet Trip file
  - Articles - Brazil, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Books and Pamphlets - Brazil, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Democracy in Communication: Popular Video and Film in Latin America, Traveling Exhibition, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Enúgbárijo Comunicações, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - A Fundação Ford: No Rio de Janeiro, Brasil, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Brazilian Media Grant Listing, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Itinerary for Brazil Trip, 1989 March 1-12 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Brewer Media - Consulting, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Media (Brazil), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Memos (In-House) - Brazil Media Consultancy, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Memos/Letters from the Brewers, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Memos/Letters to the Brewers, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Notes - Brazil Media Projects, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Rebecca Reichmann, Brazil Office, Memos, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - An Evaluation of the Use of Video in Popular Movements in Brazil, Michael and Geovanni Brewer, 1989 March (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - An Evaluation of the Use of Video in Popular Movements in Brazil, Michael and Geovanni Brewer - Drafts, 1989 March (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Brazilian Association for Video in Popular Movements (RGA), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Brazil Meeting - June 12 (Rubber Tappers), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Innovations in State and Local Government, 1986-1992; 3; 5.85 Cubic Feet 14 letter document boxes and 1 half-box
  Biographical / Historical
  In 1986, the Ford Foundation, with the assistance of the John F. Kennedy School of Government at Harvard University, initiated an awards program on Innovations in State and Local Government. The objective of the program was to demonstrate that government is capable of responding creatively and effectively to critical social issues. Each winning program received a Foundation grant of $100,00 to disseminate information about the program and encourage its replication. From 1986 until 1995 (with a hiatus in 1989), the awards honored ten states, cities, counties, and tribal or public authorities for exemplary innovative programs. In 1995, the Foundation expanded the number of $100,000 awards from ten to 15 and began honoring federal Innovations as well.
  The Foundation undertook a variety of outreach activities in support of the Innovations Program. It hired a public relations firm to disseminate information about award-winners, finalists, and semi-finalists, and to promote awareness of the program in the popular media and trade press. It also sponsored a program booklet to publicize Innovations programs that was mailed members of Congress and other government officials.
  The series contains press releases, marketing materials, planning meeting files, Innovating America by Fred Jordan book materials, Innovating America film materials, ceremony planning correspondence and invitations, press coverage analysis, articles, and background on award winners.
  - Finalists Press Releases, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Memos and Correspondence, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Slideshow, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Council on Foundations Film and Video Festival, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Book Order/Requests, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Marketing and Public Relations Program Update, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - M Booth and Associates Contract, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - M Booth Extension of Agreement and Agreement, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - M Booth Invoices, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - M Booth and Associates, Inc. Marketing Meeting, 1990 May 7 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - M Booth and Associates Media Campaign, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - M Booth and Associates Monthly Activity Reports and Updates, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - M Booth and Associates Monthly Planning Meetings, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - STEP Program Minnesota, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Newsletter Alumni Association, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Program Book Hollyman/Steinbach, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Recommendations for Grant Action (RGAs), 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Survey, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Advertising, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - AdMaster, Inc. Orientation, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Survey Research Proposals, 1990 July 25 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - AdMaster, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Marketing Plans, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Proposals - Hill and Knowlton, Powell, Adams and Rinehart, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Innovating America - Film Distribution (M Booth), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Innovating America - Modern Talking Picture Service Catalog, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Innovating America - Film Request/Screening, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Innovating America - Contacts, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Innovating America - Discussion Guide, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 66-67)
  - Fred Jordan - "The Public Purse", 1990 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Innovating America - Media Book Tour, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Innovating America - Newsletter Proposal: Fred Jordan, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Innovating America - Fred Jordan Book Press Release, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Innovating America - Fred Jordan, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Innovating America - Book: Media Tour, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Innovations in State and Local Government - Film, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Brazil - Media, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Clippings, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Innovating America Film - Letters: W. Milliken, F. Thomas, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Innovating America - Guide, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Steinbach, Carol F. Brochure, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Dedication of the A. Alfred Taubman Building at Harvard University, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Letter from Andrea Taylor to William G. Milliken, 1990 March 16 (Box 9, Folder 113)
  - 25 Innovations Finalists, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 114)
  - Innovating America, Part II Discussion Guide, Fred Jordan, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 115)
  - Fred Jordan Book Outline (Rough Draft), 1990 (Box 9, Folder 116)
  - Fred Jordan Writing Samples, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - Fred Jordan Correspondence and Notes, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 118)
  - Innovations Film, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - Innovating America Narration, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 120)
  - Innovations Seminar (Northern Light), 1989 March (Box 9, Folder 121)
  - Northern Light Productions Agreement, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 122)
  - Innovations Awards Kick-off Event, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 123)
  - Lessons Learned from the First Three Years of Innovations Research, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 124)
  - Innovations Logos, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 125)
  - Innovations Luncheon, 1989 April-May (Box 10, Folder 126)
  - Computer Assisted Report Entry (CARE), St. Louis County Police Department pamphlet, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 127)
  - One Church, One Child, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 128)
  - Parents as Teachers, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 129)
  - Professional Conferences, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 130)
  - Innovations Program Proposal, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 131)
  - The City of San Diego's Single Room Occupancy Residential Hotel Program, 1988-1990 (Box 10, Folder 132)
  - Strive Toward Excellence in Performance (STEP), State of Minnesota, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 133)
  - Tupelo, Mississippi, Public/Private Partnerships in Education, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 134)
  - Innovations Winners, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 135)
  - Innovations Notes, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 136)
  - Innovating America - Show #1, 1989 December 1; U-matic (Box 1, Tape AV 13074)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Open for research. Digital access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  - Innovating America - Show #2, 1989 December 1; U-matic (Box 1, Tape AV 13075)
  - Innovating America - Show 1 - Offline and Graphics, 1989 November 5; U-matic (Box 1, Tape AV 13076)
  - Innovating America - Show 2 Offline and Graphics, 1989 November 5; U-matic (Box 1, Tape AV 13077)
  - Innovating America - Show 2 Offline - Without Music Graphics, Ch 1 and 2, 1989 November 8; U-matic (Box 1, Tape AV 13078)
  - Northern Lights - Innovating America Show #1, 1990 February 12; U-matic; 30 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13079)
  - Northern Lights - Innovating America Show #2, 1990 February 12; U-matic; 30 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13080)
  - Innovations Arrangements - Proofs for Committee, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 137)
  - 1988 Innovations Award Finalists (Box 10, Folder 138)
  - Suggested Remarks for Innovations Program Awards Presentation, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 139)
  - 1988 Innovations Awards Program (Box 11, Folder 140)
  - 1988 Innovations Award Winners (Box 11, Folder 141)
  - 1988 Innovations Award Ceremony Work Schedule (Box 11, Folder 142)
  - Innovations Program Brochure, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 143)
  - Innovations - Governing Magazine, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 144)
  - Innovations - National Journal, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 145)
  - Innovations - Program Books, 1986-1988 (Box 11, Folder 146)
  - Innovations Books - Reader's Digest, 1988 September (Box 12, Folder 147)
  - Innovations 1988 - Ways and Means, National Center for Policy Alternatives Journal (Box 12, Folder 148)
  - Innovations 1988 - Award Ceremony Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 149)
  - Innovations 1988 - Feedback, 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 150)
  - Innovations 1988 - General Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 151)
  - Innovations 1988 - Invitation Letters (Guest List) (Box 12, Folder 152)
  - Innovations 1988 - Northern Light Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 153)
  - Innovations 1988 - Notes, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 154)
  - Innovations 1988 - Articles, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 155)
  - Innovations 1988 - Ford Foundation Letter/Article by Robert Tolles (Box 12, Folder 156)
  - Innovations 1988 - KQED Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 157)
  - Innovations 1988 - Media Briefing (Box 12, Folder 158)
  - Innovations 1988 - Meetings with Innovation Winners on Capitol Hill (Box 12, Folder 159)
  - Innovations 1988 - News Releases (Drafts and Finals) (Box 12, Folder 160)
  - Innovations 1988 - News Releases (Faxed) (Box 13, Folder 161)
  - Innovations 1988 - Press Conference, 1988 September 30 (Box 13, Folder 162)
  - Innovations 1988 - Press Event (Box 13, Folder 163)
  - State-to-State Television Series Letter, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 164)
  - Government Projects, 1987-1990 (Box 13, Folder 165)
  - Northern Light Productions - Award Film: Treatment, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 166)
  - David Arnold - Speech, East Suburban Council for Open Communities, Cleveland, 1989 February (Box 33, Folder 429)
  - Innovations 1990 - Slide Show Correspondence (Box 33, Folder 430)
  - A. Alfred Taubman Building Dedication, Harvard University, 1990 September (Box 33, Folder 431)
  - Innovations 1990 - Advertising (Box 33, Folder 432)
  - Innovations 1990 - Awards Presentation Ceremony (Box 33, Folder 433)
  - Innovations 1990 - Contact Persons for Recipients of Awards (Box 33, Folder 434)
  - Innovating America - Distribution of Book and Video, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 435)
  - Ford Foundation Letter Schedule, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 436)
  - Innovating America, Fred Jordan Manuscript Information, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 437)
  - Innovations 1990 - Stephanie Hollyman Photographer, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 438)
  - Innovations 1989 - Case Studies/Videos (Box 33, Folder 439)
  - Innovations Press Coverage, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 440)
  - List of Addresses of National Committee Members, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 441)
  - Letters Requesting Review of Edited Version of Fred Jordan's Innovating America, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 442)
  - Strategy, Innovation, and Inertia: Unbundling Some Old Assumptions, Mark Zegans Speech, 1990 October 18 (Box 33, Folder 443)
  - Innovating America - Video and Book Marketing - Direct Mail, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 444)
  - Mechanicals for the Innovating America Label and Video Wrapper, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 445)
  - Motion Pictures Registration Claims to Copyright, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 446)
  - News Releases, 1991-1992 (Box 33, Folder 447)
  - News Release - Press Packet for Innovations, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 448)
  - Past Innovations Award Winners, 1986-1992 (Box 33, Folder 449)
  - Innovating America - Printing Costs and Schedule, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 450)
  - Requests to View Innovating America Video, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 451)
  - Innovations 1991 - Mailing List Additions (Box 47, Folder 625)
  - Innovations 1991 - Awardees Contact Info (Box 47, Folder 626)
  - Innovations 1991 - Memoranda (Box 47, Folder 627)
  - Innovations 1991 - Seminars/Panel Discussion for Winners at Helmsley Hotel (Box 47, Folder 628)
  - Innovations 1991 - Innovations in State and Local Government Program Book, 1990-1991 (Box 47, Folder 629)
  - Innovations 1991 - Slide Show/Admaster (Box 47, Folder 630)
  - Innovations 1991 - Invitation (Box 47, Folder 631)
  - Innovations 1991 - Photo Exhibit (Box 47, Folder 632)
  - Innovations 1991 - Press Releases - Drafts (Box 47, Folder 633)
  - Innovations 1991 - New York Times Ad (Box 47, Folder 634)
  - Innovations 1991 - Governing Magazine Ad (Box 47, Folder 635)
  - Innovations 1991 - Press Releases (Box 47, Folder 636)
  - Innovations in State and Local Government Awards Program: UPDATE 1990, A Report to the National Advisory Committee, 1991 June (Box 47, Folder 637)
  - Innovations in State and Local Government Marketing and Public Relations Program Update, 1990 July-1991 July (Box 47, Folder 638)
  - Ford/Innovations Breakfast Meeting, 1991 (Box 47, Folder 639)
  - Sent Innovations Material, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 640)
  - Innovations 1991 - Media Coverage, 1991-1992 (Box 48, Folder 641)
  - Innovations 1991 - Media Results (Box 48, Folder 642)
  - Public Innovations and the Media: Stimulus or Barrier?, University of Washington Forum, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 643)
  - Innovations 1992 - Memos and Background Materials (Box 48, Folder 644)
  - Innovations 1992 - Marketing Plan, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 645)
  - Innovations Op-Ed Piece, Henry Cisnerros, 1991 November (Box 48, Folder 646)
  - Innovations 1991 - Traveling Photographic Exhibit (Box 48, Folder 647)
  - Innovations 1990 - Funding Proposals (Box 48, Folder 648)
  - Innovations 1991 - Marketing and Public Relations Program, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 649)
  - Innovating America - Fred Jordan Book Distribution, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 650)
  - Innovating America - Nomination to the Film and Video Festival, Council on Foundations, 1990-1991 (Box 48, Folder 651)
  - Innovating America - Fred Jordan Conference Report, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 652)
  - Bruce Weber, Story Editor, New York Times Magazine, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 653)
  - Summary of Innovations Marketing and Public Relations by M Booth and Associates, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 654)
  - Innovations - Breaking through Bureaucracy, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 655)
  - Innovating America - Film Distribution, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 656)
  - News Releases - Semifinalists, 1991-1992 (Box 48, Folder 657)
  - Innovations 1991 - Letters Announcing Semifinalists (Box 48, Folder 658)
  - Innovations 1991 - Memos, 1991-1992 (Box 49, Folder 659)
  - Innovations 1991 - M Booth, Ford, and Innovations Program Meeting (Box 49, Folder 660)
  - Innovations 1991 - Marketing and Public Relations Program, 1990-1991 (Box 49, Folder 661)
  - Innovations 1991 - Marketing and Public Relations Program - William G. Milliken Op-Ed, 1990-1991 (Box 49, Folder 662)
  - Innovations 1991 - Application Review Planning (Box 49, Folder 663)
  - Innovations 1991 - Carol Steinbach, Direct Deposit for the Poor Editorial (Box 49, Folder 664)
  - Innovations 1991 and 1992 - Awards, 1991-1992 (Box 49, Folder 665)
  - Innovations 1991 - Draft Op-Ed by Marc Zegans (Box 49, Folder 666)
  - Innovations 1991 - Press Clippings (Box 49, Folder 667)
  - The Fundamental Issues of Innovation, Duke University Conference, 1991 (Box 49, Folder 668)
  - Girls, Inc. - Hard Hats and Lab Coats: Creating Opportunities for Girls in Science, Math, and Technology, Amy Sutnick, 1991 (Box 49, Folder 669)
  - JFK School of Government, Harvard - Technology-Based Innovation - When Times are Tough Conference, 1991 (Box 49, Folder 670)
  - Innovations 1991 - Meeting, 1991 May 16 (Box 49, Folder 671)
  - Innovations 1991 - Profiles of Innovations Winners, Carol Steinbach (Box 49, Folder 672)
  - Innovations 1991 - Agenda, 1991 July (Box 50, Folder 673)
  - Innovations 1991 - Susan Berresford Talking Points (Box 50, Folder 674)
  - Innovations 1991 - Winners Applications (Box 50, Folder 675)
  - Innovations 1991 - Marc Zegans Op-Ed (Box 50, Folder 676)
  - Innovations 1990 - October 1990 Governing Magazine Cover Story (Box 50, Folder 677)
  - Innovations - Miscellaneous, 1989-1992 (Box 50, Folder 678)
- Changing Relations Project, America Becoming Documentary, 1983-1991; 4; 1.52 Cubic Feet 4 letter document boxes
  In 1987, in response to increasing immigration in the 1980s, the Ford Foundation provided a grant to the State University of New York to study the relationships and everyday interactions among recent immigrants and longer-term residents. The Changing Relations project employed ethnographic research methods in Chicago, Houston, Miami, Philadelphia, Monterey Park, California, and Garden City, Kansas. A National Board directed the project by defining its scope, organizing its research, and awarding subgrants to local research teams.
  In addition to a final report published in 1993, the project produced a 9O-minute documentary called America Becoming, which was filmed on location at the research sites and aired on public television in 1991. The documentary was directed by Charles Burnett co-written by Charles Burnett and Dai Sil Kim-Gibson.
  The series consists of files related to the 1991 documentary, America Becoming, created as part of the Ford Foundation's Changing Relations project. The series contains correspondence with writer Dai Sil Kim-Gibson, meeting materials, conference papers, news releases, project notes, reports, grant documents, and marketing documents.
  - Dai-Sil Kim-Gibson Treatments from October Meeting, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 314)
  - Dai-Sil Kim-Gibson TV Proposal, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 315)
  - Interim Report (Chicago, Garden City, Miami, Philadelphia), 1989 (Box 25, Folder 316)
  - Handwritten Notes, 1988-1989 (Box 25, Folder 317)
  - Dallas Meeting, 1989 March (Box 25, Folder 318)
  - Dissemination, 1988-1989 (Box 25, Folder 319)
  - Harvard University - Letter to Alice O'Connor from K.L. Schlozman and Sidney Verba, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 320)
  - Comments on the Houston Project, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 321)
  - Immigration - "Peopling of America": The Movie, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 322)
  - Interviews, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 323)